one question we get asked a lot is how do you know if a VS Code or Positron extension is safe
before you install it? There are thousands of extensions available in the Visual Studio
Marketplace and OpenVSX Registry. And while there's no guaranteed way to know with 100%
certainty if an extension is completely safe, here are four things you can review to try and
minimize risk. One is to make sure that the publisher ID lists the official publisher
like posit.air and look for the blue verified check mark. Two, check the download stats. Of
course more downloads doesn't always mean it's safe, but generally if it's very high the community
has already vetted it. Three, check the source repo for realistic stats and activity, active reviews,
issue tracking. Four, make sure permissions match the tool. A code formatter like air shouldn't need
full network access or background scripts. Do you have any other tips for vetting extensions?
Let us know in the comments.